Jarosław Kulik

Profile

I'm a highly experienced senior gaming industry professional with deep insight into the gaming business from the publisher's and developer's perspectives. I've participated in all phases of game development, from pitch through release and beyond. Worked on and shipped multiple titles of different scopes on every major platform and storefront. Able to build interdisciplinary teams from the ground up to solve problems and deliver products. I enjoy solving complex problems to make great products.

Experience

Sales & Business Development Manager, Artifex Mundi – 2020-current

- · Responsible for new business development
- Built sales and distribution strategy and worked on new sales opportunities
- · Worked closely with global distribution platforms and publishers

Senior Technical Producer / Business Development Manager, Artifex Mundi – 2014-2020

- Built and managed team responsible for adapting an in-house game engine to new platforms with over 50 successful releases to date (Xbox Series X|S, Xbox One, PS5, PS4, Nintendo Switch, Apple TV, Android TV, Tesla)
- Responsible for planning, prioritization and coordination of projects milestones and release schedules; provided effort estimations and cost control
- Worked closely with 3rd party developers and publishers
- Strengthened collaboration with OEM partners including Microsoft, Sony, Nintendo, Google, Apple to secure the company's access to markets and technical information
- Developed relationships with worldwide digital distribution platforms including Steam, gog.com, mail.ru, Humble Bundle, Sonkwo, etc.
- Participated and represented the company at trade fairs, conferences and other industry events

Technical Director / Associate Producer, The Farm 51 – 2011-2014

- Planned milestones and release schedules for Painkiller: Hell & Damnation and Deadfall Adventures to meet publisher quality expectations and deadlines; coordinated the development and release for PC (digital/physical), Xbox 360 (digital/physical) and PlayStation 3 (digital)
- Worked with programmers, technical artists and QAs on numerous optimization problems; oversaw content creation pipelines
- Prepared pitch decks and game design documents for publishers
- · Supported the development and release of Afterfall: InSanity (Nicolas Games)
- · Managed outsource and localization processes

Level / Gameplay Designer, The Farm 51 – 2008-2011

- Designed and scripted levels for NecroVisioN and NecroVisioN: Lost Company
- Created initial world/level designs for Gorky 21 and Alien Rage
- Co-developed multiplayer mode and levels for Two Worlds 2 (Reality Pump)

Education

Bachelor of Engineering at Silesian University of Technology – Faculty of Automatic control, Electronics and Computer Science, Gliwice, 2005-2009

Databases, Computer Networks and Systems

Skills

Comprehensive understanding of the video games market and trends; Programmers education and experience background; Proactive in problem-solving; Always involved, focused and goal-oriented; Calm of spirit and friendliness